Next, let's learn how to make a cake skirt
First, we only use the belt, so these panels of the bag skirt can be deleted
After deleting, let's draw a rectangle
Just like we drew the lotus leaf side before
This rectangle is as much wider than the belt
The height of this rectangle can be aligned with the 2D window
Then create a symmetrical panel
Then use the sewing tool to sew them together
After sewing, press Shift F to open the arrangement point
Arrange this panel on the arrangement point on the side
After arranging, because there is some gap between the body and the body
So we have to go to the attribute editor
Pull the shoulder strap of the arrangement a little further
Then press the control key to start the simulation
After the simulation, we will see that the wrinkles are very deep
So we have to reduce the particle diameter and collision thickness
After the simulation, we can see that the wrinkles will become smoother
Because we are going to make a cake skirt later
The cake skirt has many layers
There are too many wrinkles in the middle layer
So in order to prevent any instability later
We can use the tail shrink rate first
If you don't know the shrink rate
How to add the shrink rate
We can use the edit texture tool
After selecting a panel
This arrow direction is a gold shape
Since we want to shrink horizontally
That is to reduce the tail shape
When we reduce the shrink rate of the tail shape
You can see that this panel will eventually become
A very flat and tight state
Then we can freeze this panel
And copy and paste it
Directly in the 3D or 2D window
Copy and paste a layer of panel
Then activate this panel
Rearrange it
When you are arranging the panel
Be sure to change the perspective
See if there is any overlap in other places
If it doesn't work on one arrangement point
We can adjust other arrangement points
Then re-use the line shrink tool
To sew them together
Here we have to pay attention
Because it is now in the top right corner
Is folded
So we have to put it
Shrink line type
Changed to turn
After opening the simulation
We will find that it is particularly stable here
Then we can adjust
The length of the outer panel
After that
Activate the inner panel panel
Let's simulate it together
Then we can
Little by little
Change the tail shrink rate of the inner layer
Pay attention
It is best to use time as a unit
Little by little
Simulate and enlarge at the same time
Don't put too much at once
Otherwise there may be instability
Now we have done three layers
After making the three-layer structure
If we activate the belt now
And after opening the simulation
We will find that the belt will fall down
Because of the weight of other fabrics
In order to prevent the belt from deforming
We need to copy a fabric
And change the attribute of this fabric
To Fusible Rigid
Fusible Rigid
It will gradually shrink inwards, and it won't be as strong as it was before
You may be more curious about how I adjust this skirt if I want to increase its
How do I adjust it? It's actually very simple
For a rectangular skirt like this, you just need to stretch it a little bit and you can add creases
But be careful not to pull too much at a time. If you pull too much, the skirt will be pierced and the final simulation may be unstable